

Nelson Nunes

Senior Software Developer Cape Town, South Africa

I am a multifaceted, passionate & enthusiastic individual who started my programming career because of my hate for computers. At the start of my higher education (and typical of most students), my focus reflected in my results. After failing to secure a secondary "Parental Bursary", I started my employment career. To keep my mind stimulated, I decided to do a short course and, hating computers, I picked C & C++ programming. I fell in love with the art of programming. I see programming as an art form. With the screen my canvas, the code my brushes, I embraced the journey of coding art. After 14 years of a genuinely illustrious career in software development, I fell on hard times and find myself unemployed. I undertake to follow my dreams once again and begin my journey as an entrepreneurial renegade. Entrepreneurship is no walk in the park and one of the unavoidable side effects that goes along with being an entrepreneur, is failure and loss. Many let failure knock them down, and at first I was no different, however, I always keep getting up, learning and growing. "I didn't fail the test, I just found 100 ways to do it wrong" - Benjamin Franklin.

Experience

Senior Software Developer

iOCO

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2022

Senior Software Developer Capricorn Bank

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

Senior Software Developer (Team Lead)

Vodacom

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) May 2021 - Oct 2021

Senior Software Developer

AngloAmerican

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

Senior Software Developer

Sanlam

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Entrepreneur

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Education

University of Stellenbosh

Certificate

2022 - 2022

Business and System Analysis

Udemy

Certificate

2020 - 2020

Master ASP.NET MVC Core 3.1

Udemv

Certificate

2020 - 2020

Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer

Udemy

Certificate

2020 - 2020

RESTful Web services with ASP.NET Core

Udemv

Certificate

2019 - 2019

React - The Complete Guide (incl. Hooks, React Router, Redux)

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2012 - 2012 SCRUM

Uber Driver/Partner

UBER

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2016 - Oct 2018 1663 trips completed.

One of the highest rated Uber Drivers in South Africa, with a rating of 4.9

Entrepreneur

Oteka

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Apr 2014 - Sep 2016

Senior Solutions Developer/Consultant

Asyst International

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Oct 2012 - Mar 2014

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Jan 2011 - Sep 2012

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes (UK)

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Feb 2010 - Dec 2011

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa (Hybrid) Jan 2008 - Jan 2010

Intermediate Software Developer

Dimension Data

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2005 - Dec 2007

Software Developer

The Workforce Group

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 1999 - Sep 2005

Skills

.NET Framework (C#)

.NET Core (C#)

Amazon DynamoDB

Angular

ASP.NET (C#)

AWS

Azure

CSS/Bootstrap

JavaScript

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010 ITIL 3.0

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010 COBIT 5.0

Microsoft

Certificate

2000 - 2000

MVP - Visual Basic 6.0

Boston City Campus

Certificate

1999 - 1999

C & C++ Programming

West Ridge High School

Matric

1991 - 1996

Contact

nelson@nelsonunes.dev

+27 65 889 6633

Cape Town, South Africa

https://github.com/nelsonunes-dev

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nelsonunes/

https://nelsonunes.dev

Microsoft SQL Server

MongoDB

MySQL

NodeJS

PostgreSQL

React

Typescript

Xamarin